Guide to the Printmakers Gathering Portfolio
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Printmakers Gathering Portfolio
1995-2011
GEN MSS 1474
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2
(1 box)
Inkjet prints created in 2011 by printmakers of their own black-and-white photographic work, 1995-2011, that they compiled as portfolios and exchanged in conjunction with the meeting of the Society of Photographic Educators in Atlanta, Georgia, March 2011.
Blackwell, Walker
Boley, Tyler
Cone, Jon, 1957-
Dean, John, photographer
Henkin, Lauren, 1974-
Kennedy, Bill, 1951 April 7-
King, J. Scott, photographer
Savoia, Mark
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Lauren Henkin, 2017.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by printmaker.
Content Description
Inkjet prints created in 2011 by printmakers of their own black-and-white photographic work, 1995-2011, that they compiled as portfolios and exchanged in conjunction with the meeting of the Society of Photographic Educators in Atlanta, Georgia, March 2011. Individuals with work represented in the portfolio include Walker Blackwell, Tyler Boley, Jon Cone, John Dean, Lauren Henkin, Bill Kennedy, J. Scott King, and Mark Savoia. The guide to the collection includes descriptions of image capture techniques, scanner technologies, and printer methods. Cone summarized some of the printing methods in his "The State of the State of the Arts in Black & White" in View Camera Magazine (January/February 2012).
Ownership & Copyright
The Printmakers Gathering Portfolio is the physical property of the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors or their legal heirs and assigns. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Ink-jet printing; Landscape photography; Prints -- Technique; Inkjet prints; Photographs; Henkin, Lauren, 1974-; Blackwell, Walker; Boley, Tyler; Cone, Jon, 1957-; Dean, John, photographer; Henkin, Lauren, 1974-; Kennedy, Bill, 1951 April 7-; King, J. Scott, photographer; Savoia, Mark
- Inkjet Prints, 1995–2011
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by printmaker.
  - Blackwell, Walker
    Biographical / Historical
    Walker Blackwell is a printmaker, educator, and founder of Black Point Editions in Chicago.
    - Shadow Portrait #1, Chicago, Il, printed in 2011 February; image created in 2004; 1 inkjet print, 51 x 41 cm (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      From a body of work, Shadow Portraits.
      Photographic image created with a Hasselblad 500 C camera and 60-millimeter lens on Kodak T-MAX 100 film, scanned using Scanview ScanMate 11000 scanner, and printed by an Epson Stylus Pro 4000 using ErgoSoft Studio Print Raster Image Processing Software on Canson Infinity Rag Photographique 210 grams per square meter matte paper using PiezoTone Selenium K7 ink.
    - Cement #1, Chicago, Il, printed in 2011 February; image created in 2005; 1 inkjet print, 51 x 41 cm (Box 1, Folder 2)
      From a body of work, Cement.
      Photographic image created with a Hasselblad 500 C camera and 60-millimeter lens on Kodak T-MAX 100 film, scanned using Scanview ScanMate 11000 scanner, and printed by an Epson Stylus Pro 9900 using ColorBurst Raster Image Processing software on Epson Exhibition Fiber Paper using Epson UltraChrome High Dynamic Range ink and Cone Editions Gloss Optimizer.
  - Boley, Tyler
    Tyler Boley is a photographer, printmaker, educator, and founder of Custom Digital LLC.
    - Elizabeth G 26, printed in 2011 March; image created in 2010; 1 inkjet print, 51 x 41 cm (Box 1, Folder 3)
      From a series of eight images, Elizabeth G.
      Printed on Arches Natural White Cold Press Watercolor Paper using Epson UltraChrome High Dynamic Range ink.
    - Vantage WA 3, printed in 2011 February; image created in 1995; 1 inkjet print, 41 x 51 cm (Box 1, Folder 4)
      From an ongoing body of work of Pacific Northwest landscapes.
      Printed on Canson Infinity Edition Etching Rag 210 grams per square meter paper using a custom ink blend of Cone PiezoTone Warm Neutral, Cone PiezoTone Carbon Sepia, Cone PiezoTone Selenium Tone, and Cone Piezography Sepia K7 ink.
  - Cone, Jon
    Jon Cone is a artist, printmaker, developer of technology, and educator.
    - First Snow, printed in 2011; image created in 2010; 1 inkjet print, 41 x 51 cm (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Alternate title on verso, My trees off the old county road.
      Custom monochromatic process on handmade paper.
  - Dean, John
    John Dean is a photographer, printmaker, and founder of Dean Imaging.
    - Three Mountain Huts, printed in 2011 February; image created in 2008; 2 inkjet prints, 51 x 41 cm (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
      From series Buildings in Motion.
      Photographic image created with a Horseman 450 camera and a 90-millimeter Rodenstock Grandagon lens on Ilford HPS film, scanned using a Howtek drum scanner and printed by a Hewlett Packard DesignJet 23100 printer using Qimage Ultimate software on Canson Infinity Rag Photographique 210 grams per square meter matte paper using Hewlett Packard Vivera ink and coated with Moab Desert Varnish Lacquer.
    - Tsunami Village, printed in 2011 February; image created in 2008; 1 inkjet print, 41 x 51 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Print made with Split QuadTone Raster Image Processing software using Cone Piezography Warm Neutral K7 and Cone Piezography Selenium K7 ink
    - Untitled, printed in 2011 February; image created in 2010 December; 1 inkjet print, 41 x 51 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
      From series Before and After Pangaea that looks at isolated geological formations in the Appalachian Mountains.
      Photographic image created with a Wista 45 camera and a 90-millimeter Rodenstock Grandagon lens on Kodak T-MAX 100 film, scanned using a Howtek drum scanner and printed by a Hewlett Packard DesignJet Z3100 Photo Printer using Qimage Ultimate software on Cone 55 natural gloss fiber rag paper and coated with Moab Desert Varnish Lacquer.
  - Henkin, Lauren
    Lauren Henkin is a photographer and sculptor.
    - Night Light, printed 2011 March 6; image created in 2007; 1 inkjet print, 41 x 51 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
      From series Displaced Part I, image created in Nova Scotia, Canada.
      Photographic image created with a Wista 45 camera, printed by an Epson Stylus Pro 4800 printer using QuadTone Raster Image Processing Software on Hahnemühle William Turner Inkjet Paper.
    - Silence is an Orchard 14, printed 2011 March 2; image created in 2008; 1 inkjet print, 51 x 41 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
      From series Silence is an Orchard.
      Image created in Acadia National Park.
      Photographic image created with a Wista 45 camera, printed by an Epson Stylus Pro 4800 printer using QuadTone Raster Image Processing Software on kozo paper.
  - Kennedy, Bill
    Bill Kennedy is a photographer and printmaker.
    - Highway 182 #3, printed 2011 March; image created in 2008; 1 inkjet print, 51 x 41 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Image created in Louisiana.
      Photographic image created with a Wista 45 camera and a 135-millimeter Fujinon lens on Kodak color negative film, and printed by an Epson Stylus Pro 9600 using OpenPrintMaker software on Hahnemühle bamboo paper using Cone Piezography Sepia K7 ink.
    - Gail, printed 2011 March; image created in 2011; 1 inkjet print, 41 x 51 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Image created in Austin, Texas.
      Photographic image created with a Arca-Swiss camera and a Kodak Portrait lens through digital capture with a Better Light Super 6K-HS and printed by an Epson Stylus Pro 9800 using ColorBurst Raster Image Processing software on Canson Infinity BFK Rives Paper using ConeColor ink.
  - King, J. Scott
    J. Scott King is a photographer and printmaker.
    - Quebec City, printed 2011 March; image created in 1996; 1 inkjet print, 51 x 41 cm (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Image created in Quebec, Canada.
      Photographic image created with a Leica M6 camera and a Summicron-M 35-millimeter lens on Ilford HP5 Plus film, and printed by an Epson Stylus Pro 9600 using OpenPrintMaker software on Hahnemühle bamboo paper using Cone Piezography Sepia K7 ink.
    - Lauren Torso, printed 2011 March; image created in 2007; 1 inkjet print, 41 x 51 cm (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Photographic image created with a Leica M8 camera and a Summicron-M 35-millimeter lens through digital capture and printed by an Epson Stylus Pro 9800 using ColorBurst Raster Image Processing software on Canson Infinity BFK Rives Paper using ConeColor ink.
  - Savoia, Mark
    Mark Savoia is a photographer and printmaker.
    - Fried Doe, Just a Buck, printed 2010 February; image created in 2006; 1 inkjet print, 41 x 51 cm (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Photographic image created on 35-millimeter film and scanned using a Howtek drum scanner printed by an Epson Stylus Pro 9800 using Studio Print Version 12 software on Hahnemühle Photo Gloss Baryta 320 grams per square meter paper using Cone PiezoTone Carbon Sepia ink and coated with ultraviolet varnish